Manuel Menéndez

Software developer living in Barcelona. More than 5 years of experience working in teams and implementing CI/CD. Good background in functional programming. Capable of managing projects from concept to completion, as well as joining on course projects. Experience with relational and non-relational databases, developing, testing and deploying code. Always willing to learn.

Excellent personal skills, empathy and a compatible team player. Passionate about Elixir/OTP and all kinds of topics related to backend and database engineering. Continuous focus on developing my analytical skills and problem solving capacities.

Agullers 8, 2, 08003, Barcelona, Spain

+34638465102

manuelmenendezalfonso@gmail. com

github.com/hudsonbay

linkedin.com/in/manuel-menend ez-alfonso

youtube.com/channel/UChznmZd 5D9lqUvN3-fh0KRA

medium.com/@hudsonbay

EXPERIENCE

Kantox, Spain — Software Engineer

ABR 2022 - PRESENT

Working on a strategic project that sends hedge recommendations based on clients hedging strategies. Collaborating with cross-functional teams like frontend, product, cloud, QA and management. Working with Elixir/Phoenix, ES/CQRS, REST APIs, LiveView, Gherkin/Cucumber for acceptance tests, PostgreSQL, ETS, InfluxDB, RabbitMQ, OpenTelemetry, Grafana, AWS.

Zubale, USA — Software Engineer

MAY 2021 - ABR 2022

Helping enhancing and scaling the engineering strategy. Working in a very dynamic position by taking care of different microservices using Elixir/OTP, Phoenix, Apache Kafka, Elasticsearch. PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Redis and GraphQL. Integrating external APIs and services with the platform. Improving DB performance, designing systems and more.

Joven Club Central (National Development Team), Cuba — Full-stack Developer

MAY 2017 - MAY 2021

Development of different admin frontend web apps (Vue/React), Android apps (Java/Kotlin), and REST APIs (Elixir/Phoenix, Node.js). Capturing business rules from the clients and translating it into software that solves their needs.

SKILLS

Elixir, OTP, Phoenix, LiveView

ES/CQRS

Docker, Github Actions

AWS, Grafana

HAProxy, Keepalive, Ansible

RabbitMQ, Kafka, Redis

GNU/Linux

Elasticsearch

postgreSQL, MySQL, SQLite, MongoDB

Human relationships, collective property, empathy, initiative to hangout with the team

Passion for teaching

Freelancer, Havana — Full Stack Developer

MAY 2017 - PRESENT

Worked in projects for different clients having these responsibilities:

- Develop GraphQL APIs using Elixir/Phoenix (Absinthe) and REST APIs using Express.js (Node.js)
- Web development using React.js and Vue.js
- Develop GIS applications using Folium (Python), Vue and Leaflet.js

LANGUAGES

Spanish (Native)

English (IELTS B2)

French (DELF A2)

Portuguese

EDUCATION

Technological University of Havana, Havana — *Bsc. Computer Science Engineering*

SEPTEMBER 2011 - FEBRUARY 2017

CERTIFICATIONS

Producciones Abdala S.A., Havana — Recording Assistant Certification

2014

Virtalus LLC, Los Angeles, CA — Virtalus Certified Cloud Engineer





URL Verification:

https://training.virtalus.com/mod/customcert/verify_certificate.php?contextid=385

Code: n5qPx7Eg9q

2020

HOBBIES

Meditation, swimming, martial arts, watch gameplays, GTA V, table tennis, play music, listen to new music, concerts

TECH I'M INTERESTED ON LEARN

Go deeper into database engineering and proxies